CLIFTON MATUSZEWSKI

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

615-796-5865

✓ cliftonmatuszewski@gmail.com

https://github.com/Theskiman

in linkedin.com/in/clifton-matuszewski/

https://theskiman.github.io/personal-website/

Personal Profile

I love to build and create with technology. For 7 years I have enjoyed the hobby of building computers from scratch. I enjoyed the process of putting together a giant puzzle with unique pieces and getting a finished working product. Stepping into the software development industry has allowed me to take this process further, letting me understand the inner workings of computer software. This has given me access to greater and more complex puzzles to build and put together.

Software development has allowed me to take the hobby that I already loved and turn it into a career.

Projects

Magic Builder

When I was in middle school my Uncle introduced me to a card game called Magic the Gathering. I had an absolute blast playing it with him however I could never keep up with all the deck variations I created. With the Magic Builder I can now keep up with the different decks I created and even make up new ones. I created this project using C# ASP .NET MVC and the magicthegathering.io external API. Link: https://github.com/Theskiman/Magic-Capstone

A Novel Idea

For as long as I can Remember I have always been an avid reader. Over time however I've run into the problem of finding a good book to read. I strove to fix this issue with A Novel Idea. I built it using Javascript, React, and ReactStrap letting users search books using the Google Books API letting them see a variety of amazing books based on genre, author, or title.

Link: https://github.com/Theskiman/my-capstone

Education

Nashville Software School

Full Stack Software Developer

Middle Tennessee State University

Biology (2016-2018)

Work Experience

Nashville Software School

Software Developer, February 2019-Present

- 6 month full stack bootcamp for HTML, CSS, Javascript, ReactJs, and ADO C# .NET
- Implemented dynamic CRUD functionality into applications
- · Developed applications with HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript, and React.JS
- Used local data and external API's to create dynamic single-page web applications
- Learned Bootstrap and Reactstrap styling libraries
- Used technologies such as Grunt and Browserify
- Used Github for both group and solo projects

Group Projects

Nutshell- React

The final group project for our Front-End curriculum was to build the Nutshell project again using React this time. Three of my classmates and I created this project using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, Bootstrap, CRUD, JSON-server, HTTP-Server, VSCode, Git, GitHub.

This project was an excellent way for me to get more comfortable with React and by the end of it I fell in love with React and its streamlined way of running. I became well acquainted with React by the end and also felt more comfortable with styling. *Project Link: https://github.com/c31-bywheat/by-wheat-nutshell-react*

Bangazon Workforce

Technology Used: Visual Studio, Azure Data Studio, C# .NET, ADO.NET, ASP.NET, SQL Server

The Bangazon WorkForce Management application allows for human recourses and IT departments to list and create Training Programs, Employees, Computers, and Departments. During this sprint I increased my understanding of ASP.NET MVC applications using C#. I had a blast playing around with complicated SQL statements and also working with View Models really increased my understanding of them. Everyone in the group hopped around and helped each other with all sections but my main contribution was the department controller. This really helped with with Join SQL statements as I had to list the departments along with any employees in each department.

Project LInk: https://github.com/rioting-daisies/BangazonWorkforce

Party Fowl

Server, May 2018-Present

- · Greeted and sat guests entering Party Fowl
- · Took orders and ran food to guests
- · Helped management run shifts and train new employees.

Fazoli's

Associate Manager (2016-2018)

- Ran shifts overseeing staff of up to 10 people.
- Helped build schedules for associate and management teams.
- Kept up with paperwork for company income and deposits for each week
- · Helped take and order inventory for the store weekly

Associate (2014-2016)

· Food prep and cashier